American Philosophical Society Archives 1743-1984 APS.Archives
American Philosophical Society
- Communications, 1748-1837; III; 4.0 ln. ft.
  - Manuscript communications, 1748-1837; III.1; 3.5 ln. ft.
    - ALS to John Vaughan (translation), 1805 Sept. 19; 1.0 item; Du Pont de Nemours, Eleuthere Irenee (Box 2)
      Comments on yellow fever. English translation.
    - Sur le Formation de l'eau dans les corps animal, 1800 June 20; 1.0 item; Du Pont de Nemours, Pierre Samuel, 1739-1817 (Box 2)
      n French.
    - Sur le Formation de l'eau dans les corps animal (Concerning the Water in the Body of an Animal), 1800 June 20; 1.0 item; Du Pont de Nemours, Pierre Samuel, 1739-1817 (Box 2)
      English translation.
    - Aux Americans des Etats-Unis [re: the meaning of the words "country" and "Commonwealth"], 1815 Oct. 6; 1.0 item; Du Pont de Nemours, Pierre Samuel, 1739-1817 (Box 2)
      In hand of Alexandre Cardon de Sandrands. Originally enclosed in Du Pont de Nemours to John Vaughan, 1815 Aug. 19.
    - ALS to the American Philosophical Society, 1800 May 15; 1.0 item; Du Pont de Nemours, Pierre Samuel, 1739-1817 (Box 2)
    - ALS to the American Philosophical Society, 1800 May 22; 1.0 item; Du Pont de Nemours, Pierre Samuel, 1739-1817 (Box 2)
    - ALS to John Vaughan, inclosing AMs Sur la theorie des vents, 1801 Dec. 23; 2.0 items; Du Pont de Nemours, Pierre Samuel, 1739-1817 (Box 2)
    - ALS to John Vaughan, inclosing AMs Sur la theorie des vents (On the Theory of the Winds), 1801 Dec. 23; 1.0 item; Du Pont de Nemours, Pierre Samuel, 1739-1817 (Box 2)
    - ALS to John Vaughan, 1815 Aug. 19; 1.0 item; Du Pont de Nemours, Pierre Samuel, 1739-1817 (Box 2)
    - ALS to John Vaughan, 1815 Nov. 23; 1.0 item; Du Pont de Nemours, Pierre Samuel, 1739-1817 (Box 2)
    - Meteorological observations, 1803 June 12-12.30; 1.0 item; Ecroyd, Richard (Box 2)
    - Memoir on the non-strangulating hernia and the mode of curing it, 1822 Dec. 6; 1.0 item; Elkendorp, B. (Box 2)
    - ALS to Robert Patterson, 1800 Mar. 23; 1.0 item; Ellicott, Andrew, 1754-1820 (Box 2)
    - Observations on a lunar eclipse made at Philadelphia by Robert Patterson and Ellicott, 1801 Dec. 18; 1.0 item; Ellicott, Andrew, 1754-1820 (Box 2)
    - ALS to Robert Patterson, 1801 Dec. 29; 1.0 item; Ellicott, Andrew, 1754-1820 (Box 2)
    - ALS to Thomas Jefferson, 1801 Dec. 29; 1.0 item; Ellicott, Andrew, 1754-1820 (Box 2)
    - Astronomical observations made in Lancaster, Pa. (Letterpress copy) #1, 1802 Jan. 15; 1.0 item; Ellicott, Andrew, 1754-1820 (Box 2)
    - Astronomical observations made in Lancaster, Pa. (Letterpress copy) #2, 1802 Jan. 15; 1.0 item; Ellicott, Andrew, 1754-1820 (Box 2)
    - Astronomical observations made in Lancaster, Pa. (Letterpress copy) #3, 1802 Jan. 15; 1.0 item; Ellicott, Andrew, 1754-1820 (Box 2)
    - Astronomical observations made at Lancaster, 1802 Feb. 13; 1.0 item; Ellicott, Andrew, 1754-1820 (Box 2)
    - ALS to Robert Patterson, 1802 May 3; 1.0 item; Ellicott, Andrew, 1754-1820 (Box 2)
    - Concerning the use of water for an artificial or portable horizon, 1803; 1.0 item; Ellicott, Andrew, 1754-1820 (Box 2)
    - ALS to Robert Patterson (includes John Vaughan to Ellicott, ca.1803), 1803 Oct. 1; 1.0 item; Ellicott, Andrew, 1754-1820 (Box 2)
    - ALS to Robert Patterson, 1804 Jan. 24; 1.0 item; Ellicott, Andrew, 1754-1820 (Box 2)
    - ALS to Robert Patterson, 1804 Mar. 1; 1.0 item; Ellicott, Andrew, 1754-1820 (Box 2)
    - ALS to Robert Patterson, 1805 Nov. 12; 1.0 item; Ellicott, Andrew, 1754-1820 (Box 2)
    - ALS to Robert Patterson, 1806 Aug. 1; 2.0 items; Ellicott, Andrew, 1754-1820 (Box 2)
      Note: Diagram of Eclipse observed at Lancaster, PA.
      Lancaster, A.L.S. 7p. and end. and 1p. of drawing and end. Concerning the eclipse of the sun. Cf. Minutes, p.388. Enclosed originally in letter from Ellicott to R. Patterson, Aug. 2, 1806, A. Ellicott to Robert Patterson; Aug. 2, 1806. Printed: Trans., o.s.,vol. VI, 255 ff. For report of committee, see: APS. Report...Oct. 3, 1806.
    - ALS to Robert Patterson, 1806 Aug. 2; 1.0 item; 8 x 6-1/2; Ellicott, Andrew, 1754-1820 (Box 2)
      Mathematics and Astronomy.
      Lancaster, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. Add. mutilated. Enc. Concerning the solar eclipse and remarks on Ferrer's observation of it. For enclosure, see letter from Ellicott to R. Patterson; Aug. 1, 1806.
    - ALS to Robert Patterson, 1806 Aug. 16; 1.0 item; Ellicott, Andrew, 1754-1820 (Box 2)
    - Concerning hot springs at the Cape of Good Hope, 1800 May 3; 1.0 item; Elmslie, John (Box 3)
    - ALS to Dr. Griffith, 1808 May 3; 1.0 item; Elmslie, John (Box 3)
    - Concerning meteors (1), 1833 Nov.; 1.0 item; Emerson, Gouveneur (Box 3)
    - Concerning meteors (2), 1833 Nov.; 1.0 item; Emerson, Gouveneur (Box 3)
    - Concerning the causes of fluctuation of the barometer, 1825 July 12; 1.0 item; Espy, James P., (James Pollard), 1785-1860 (Box 3)
    - Directions for making his patented screw-mill, 1806; 2.0 items; Evans, Oliver, 1755-1819 (Box 3)
      Note: includes screw-mill illustration.
    - Concerning specifications of his discovery on steam engines, n.d.; 1.0 item; Evans, Oliver, 1755-1819 (Box 3)
    - ALS to Robert Patterson, 1823 Feb. 20; 2.0 items; Ewing, James (Box 3)
      Note: includes diagrams of hydrants.
    - ALS to Joel Roberts Poinsett, 1827 Sept. 5; 1.0 item; Exter, Richard (Box 3)
    - Geographical position of various places in the western hemisphere (with partial copy), 1801 Feb. 5; 2.0 items; 16x21, 14x9; Ferrer, Jose Joaquin de (Box OS)
      Trade, Commerce, Navigation, Manufactures, Agriculture, Husbandry and Economics.
      Philadelphia, A.D.S. 2p.,end. In Spanish. Copy in part. Cf. Minutes, p.309.
    - ALS to John Vaughan (with translation), 1807 April 25; 2.0 items; Ferrer, Jose Joaquin de (Box 3)
    - ALS to Juan Vaughan, 1803 Mar. 23; 2.0 items; Ferrer, Jose Joaquin de (Box 3)
    - Astronomical observations in New York, 1808 Dec. 2; 1.0 item; 13-1/2x9; Ferrer, Jose Joaquin de (Box OS)
      Dated: April 13-April 23 1805-1806. [Read ?], Dec. 2, 1808. A.D. 1p. Cf. Minutes, p. 411 (?).
    - ALS to Thomas Jefferson, 1804 Aug. 18; 2.0 items; Finlay, William M. (Box OS)
      Mathematics and Astronomy. L.S. 8p. and add., end. Concerning astronomy. Enclosed originally in letter from Finlay to Jefferson, Aug.18, 1804.
    - ALS to Thomas Jefferson, 1804 Aug. 18; 1.0 item; Finlay, William M. (Box 3)
    - ALS to Robert Barclay, 1790 April 5; 1.0 item; Fisher, Miers (Box OS)
    - Selenotopographical fragments, 1790 July; 1.0 item; Fleckenstein, Carl Gottfried (Box 3)
    - ALS to John Vaughan, 1923 Sept. 6; 4.0 items; Fleming, George (Box 3)
      Includes 2 diagrams of "double forcing pumps".
    - Concerning looming and atmospheric refraction, 1818 Sept. 6; 2.0 items; Flint, James (Box OS)
    - The introduction of vaccination in Spain, 1802; 1.0 item; Foronda, Valentin de (Box 3)
      Medicine, Anatomy, and Physiology. D. 1p. and end. In Spanish.
    - ALS to John Vaughan, 1806 Sept. 16; 1.0 item; Foronda, Valentin de (Box 3)
    - Concerning the cure of yellow fever, 1806 Sept. 19; 1.0 item; Foronda, Valentin de (Box 3)
    - ALS to John Vaughan, 1807 Mar. 20; 1.0 item; Foronda, Valentin de (Box 3)
    - Concerning the English and Spanish languages (1), 1807 April 4; 1.0 item; Foronda, Valentin de (Box 3)
    - Concerning the English and Spanish languages (2), 1807 April 4; 1.0 item; Foronda, Valentin de (Box 3)
    - Concerning the English and Spanish languages (3), 1807 April 4; 1.0 item; Foronda, Valentin de (Box 3)
    - ALS to John Vaughan, 1807 March 6; 1.0 item; Foronda, Valentin de (Box 3)
    - Description of a machine to remove sand bars, 1820 Jan. 7; 1.0 item; Foster, Williams, Jr. (Box 3)
    - ALS to John Vaughan, 1820 Jan. 7; 2.0 items; Foster, Williams, Jr. (Box 3)
      Note: includes diagram of "Mud or River Machine"
    - Queries for the Austrian traveler destined to visit Arabia, Persia, etc., n.d.; 1.0 item; Fothergill, Anthony (Box 3)
    - Observations on the cold at Northampton of Jan. 1776, 1804 Nov. 16; 1.0 item; Fothergill, Anthony (Box 3)
    - Remarks on Mugford's rudder and the proposed notice of it by the American Philosophical Society, 1805 Feb. 15; 3.0 items; Fothergill, Anthony (Box 3)
    - Nouveau caractere d'ecriture Dans le Gout Anglais, 1781; 1.0 item; Fournier, Simon-Pierre, la jeune (Box 3)
    - Meteorological imaginations and conjectures (1), 1.0 item; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790 (Box 3)
    - Meteorological imaginations and conjectures (2), 1.0 item; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790 (Box 3)
    - ALS to Robert Patterson, 1809 Mar. 9; 1.0 item; Garnett, J. (Box 3)
    - ALS to Robert Patterson, 1806 July 17; 1.0 item; Garnett, John (Box 3)
    - ALS to Thomas C. James, 1807 Oct. 31; 1.0 item; Garnett, John (Box 3)
    - ALS to G.W. Featherstonehaugh, 1823 Mar. 23; 1.0 item; Gibson, John Bannester (Box 3)
    - ALS to William Vaughan, 1825 May 9; 1.0 item; Gilbert, Davies (Box 3)
    - ALS to John Vaughan, 1807 Nov. 23; 1.0 item; Gillespie, John D. (Box 3)
    - Observations ALS to serve for the mineralogical map of Maryland, 1807 Nov. 6; 1.0 item; Godon, Silvain (Box 3)
    - Concerning the strength of timber on a bridge, 1808 May 1; 1.0 item; Gordon, E. (Box 3)
    - To Thomas C. James, 1817 Nov. 10; 1.0 item; Graberg of Hemsö (Box 3)
    - ALS to Josef Francisco de Clados, 1812 Mar. 12; 1.0 item; Grassi, Giovanni Antonio (Box 3)
    - To Elisa J. Abel, 1828 Oct. 31; Great Falls Manufacturing Company (Box 3)
      See Mease, James to Sanseer Machine Co.; 1831 Nov. 11
    - ALS to Benjamin Franklin (with memorandum by Franklin), 1789 April 24; 1.0 item; Grier, Arthur (Box 3)
    - ALS to Benjamin Franklin, 1789 May 29; 1.0 item; Grier, Arthur (Box 3)
    - ALS to Thomas Jefferson, 1801 Oct. 8; 1.0 item; Griffith, D. (Box 3)
    - ALS to John Vaughan, 1820 April 21; 1.0 item; Griffiths, Elijah (Box 3)
    - Proposed method of ascertaining longitude, 1802; 1.0 item; Groves, Matthew C. (Box 3)
    - ALS to Robert Patterson, 1795 Nov. 30; 2.0 items; Guest, Henry (Box 3)
    - Concerning the preservation of peach trees, 1795 June 2; 1.0 item; Guest, Henry (Box 3)
    - Concerning lighthouses, 1796; 1.0 item; Guest, Henry (Box 3)
    - Concerning the preservation of meat, 1796; 1.0 item; Guest, Henry (Box 3)
    - ALS to Thomas Jefferson, 1800 Sept. 22; 1.0 item; Hall, James (Box 3)
    - ALS to the American Philosophical Society. President, 1791 Aug. 20; 1.0 item; Hall, John (Box 3)
    - ALS to American Philosophical Society, 1806 Nov. 1; 2.0 items; Hall, John Elihu (Box 3)
    - Thermometrical observations made during a voyage from Philadelphia ALS to Liverpool and back ALS to Philadelphia (1), 1818 April 3; 1.0 item; Hamilton, John (Box 3)
    - Thermometrical observations made during a voyage from Philadelphia ALS to Liverpool and back ALS to Philadelphia (2), 1818 April 3; 1.0 item; Hamilton, John (Box 3)
    - Concerning the cause of tornados by electrical discharge, 1835 Nov. 20; 1.0 item; Hare, Robert (Box 3)
    - Concerning Macuire-Princep's experiment on poisonous plants., 1830 Sept. 17; 1.0 item; Harlan, Richard (Box 3)
    - Concerning a new fossil genus of mastodon and a fossil, 1830 April 16; 1.0 item; Harlan, Richard (Box 3)
    - Concerning a new species of fresh water tortoise, 1831 Dec. 1; 1.0 item; Harlan, Richard (Box 3)
    - Concerning fossils and a new genus glires, 1825 April 1; 1.0 item; Harlan, Richard (Box 3)
    - ALS to John Kearsley Mitchell, 1833 Aug. 13; 7.0 items; Harrington, William (Box 3)
      Note: includes 6 illustrations of "fossil remains of vegetables"
    - ALS to John Vaughan, 1833 Aug. 8; 1.0 item; Harris, Thaddeus Mason (Box 3)
    - ALS to Thomas Jefferson, 1808 May 28; 1.0 item; Harrison, Samuel (Box 3)
    - ALS to Marmaduke Burrough, 1834 April 6; 1.0 item; Harry, William Cobb (Box 3)
    - ALS to unidentified correspondent, 1806 Sept. 30; 1.0 item; Hassler, F. R, (Ferdinand Rudolph), 1770-1843 (Box OS)
    - On the French weights and measures (English translation) #1, 1806 Nov.; 1.0 item; Hassler, F. R, (Ferdinand Rudolph), 1770-1843 (Box 3)
    - On the French weights and measures (English translation) #2, 1806 Nov.; 1.0 item; Hassler, F. R, (Ferdinand Rudolph), 1770-1843 (Box 3)
    - List of books concerning weights and measures, 1807 April; 1.0 item; Hassler, F. R, (Ferdinand Rudolph), 1770-1843 (Box 3)
    - Concerning books on weights and measures, 1807 April; 1.0 item; Hassler, F. R, (Ferdinand Rudolph), 1770-1843 (Box 3)
    - ALS to Robert Patterson, 1807 Aug. 10; 1.0 item; Hassler, F. R, (Ferdinand Rudolph), 1770-1843 (Box 3)
    - ALS to Robert Patterson, 1807 Sept. 29; 1.0 item; Hassler, F. R, (Ferdinand Rudolph), 1770-1843 (Box 3)
    - ALS to John Vaughan, 1831 Feb. 1; 1.0 item; Hassler, F. R, (Ferdinand Rudolph), 1770-1843 (Box 3)
    - ALS to John Vaughan, 1808 June 10; 1.0 item; Hassler, F. R, (Ferdinand Rudolph), 1770-1843 (Box 3)
    - Concerning meteoric stones (1), 1808 June 10; 1.0 item; Hassler, F. R, (Ferdinand Rudolph), 1770-1843 (Box 3)
    - Concerning meteoric stones (2), 1808 June 10; 1.0 item; Hassler, F. R, (Ferdinand Rudolph), 1770-1843 (Box 3)
    - ALS to John Vaughan, 1817 June 12; 1.0 item; Hassler, F. R, (Ferdinand Rudolph), 1770-1843 (Box 3)
    - ALS to Robert Maskell Patterson, 1828 April 19; 1.0 item; Hassler, F. R, (Ferdinand Rudolph), 1770-1843 (Box OS)
    - Concerning the improvement of navigation rivers, 1820 Mar. 23; 3.0 items; Hassler, F. R, (Ferdinand Rudolph), 1770-1843 (Box 3)
      Note: includes diagram and typed translation.
    - ALS to John Vaughan, 1800 June 20; 3.0 items; Hawkins, John J. (Box OS)
    - Plan for building a city, 1800 Sept. 19; 1.0 map, 57 x 45.5 cm; Hawkins, John J. (Box 3)
      [read] A.D.S. 4p. Cf. Minutes, pages 302, 305. For report of committee, see: APS Report of committee...; [ca. Nov. 1800].
      Realms of Gold, 2 (6).
    - ALS to John Vaughan, 1820 April 17; 4.0 items; Hentz, Nicholas Marcellus (Box 3)
      Note: includes 2 diagrams of the polyglottus of a mockingbird.
    - Concerning the telegraph, 1796 July 15; 2.0 items; Hill, Henry, 1732-1798 (Box 3)
    - On education in public schools (addressed to Thomas Jefferson), 1796 Dec. 30; 2.0 items; Hiran (Box 3)
    - ALS to William Barton, 1796 Oct. 1; 1.0 item; Hobrow, William (Box 3)
    - Thermometrical observations for Feb. 1829, 1829 Mar. 21; 1.0 item; Hodge, Hugh L. (Hugh Lenox), 1796-1873 (Box 3)
    - Thermometrical observations, 1829 Jan.-March; 1.0 item; Hodge, Hugh L. (Hugh Lenox), 1796-1873 (Box 3)
    - Astronomical observations, 1772 Feb. 7; 1.0 item; Holland, Samuel (Box OS)
    - ALS to Benjamin Vaughan, 1825 Oct. 7; 1.0 item; Holmes, Ezekiel (Box 3)
    - Concerning telegraphy [received from William Dunbar, 1801 January 16], 1684 May 21; 1.0 item; Hooke, Robert (Box 3)
    - Concerning a portion of the muscular structure of the eye-lids, 1822 Mar. 1; 1.0 item; Horner, William Edmonds (Box 3)
    - ALS to John Vaughan, 1803 Sept. 3; 1.0 item; Horsfield, Timothy (Box 3)
      Medicine, Anatomy, and Physiology. Batavia, A.L.S. 8p., end. Concerning vaccinations. Natural history and description of Batavia.
    - ALS to John Vaughan, 1803 Nov. 26; 1.0 item; Horsfield, Timothy (Box 3)
    - ALS to James Gregory, 1799 Mar. 12; 1.0 item; Hosack, David (Box 3)
    - ALS to Colin Chisholm, 1812 July 10; 1.0 item; Hosack, David (Box 3)
    - ALS to David Rittenhouse, 1773; 1.0 item; Houston, William Churchill (Box 3)
    - How to ascertain the longitude, n.d.; 1.0 item (Box 3)
    - Concerning iron ore and forges in Pennsylvania, 1807; 1.0 item; Howell, James (Box 3)
    - Map of the lower Mississippi up to the Natchez, 1807; 1.0 map, 44.5 x 34.3 cm; Hulings, William E. (Box OS)
      The meridian of New Orleans is given. On the reverse is a note to John Vaughan from Hulings: "I have marked the situation of Mr. [William] D [unbar] 's place on the second Creek, but am unable to do it with Geometrical precision."
      Realms of Gold, 2 (4).
    - ALS to David Rittenhouse, 1789 Jan. 3; 1.0 item; Humphreys, Joshua (Box 4)
    - ALS to Benjamin Franklin, 1789 Feb. 16; 1.0 item; Humphreys, Joshua (Box 4)
    - ALS to John Vaughan, 1814 Mar. 25; 2.0 items; Humphreys, Joshua (Box 4)
      Note: includes a diagram of "a circular cylinder pump"
    - Concerning placing masts in ships, 1822 Jan. 18; 1.0 item; Humphreys, Samuel (Box 4)
    - Description of a model for steering a ship, 1809 Mar. 2; 2.0 items; Humphries, James Jr. (Box OS)
    - ALS to John Ewing, 1771 Dec. 26; 1.0 item; Hutchins, Thomas (Box 4)
    - ALS to Charles Willson Peale, 1797 May 25; 1.0 item; Hutchinson, S. F. (Box OS)
    - Description of a ship pump, 1797 Dec. 15; 1.0 item; Improvement (pseud) (Box OS)
    - Moulin sans meule, 1827 Dec.; 1.0 item; Institut de France. (Box 4)
    - Extract of process verbaux, 180_ Dec. 3; 1.0 item; Institut de France. Academie des inscriptions et belle-lettres (Box 4)
    - ALS to the American Philosophical Society, 1769 Jan. 10; 1.0 item; Jacobs, Benjamin. (Box 4)
    - ALS to the American Philosophical Society (with translation), 1829 Dec. 3; 1.0 item; Jaeckel, Joseph (Box OS)
    - Meteorological observations made by David Jameson and John Page, 1772; 1.0 item; Jameson, David (Box 4)
    - Petition to United States. House and Senate, 1800 Jan. 17; 1.0 item; Jefferson, Thomas. (Box 4)
    - ALS to Robert Patterson, 1802 Oct. 16; 1.0 item; Jefferson, Thomas. (Box 4)
    - ALS to Dr. Caspar Wistar, 1806 Nov. 2; 3.0 items; Jefferson, Thomas. (Box 4)
    - ALS to Robert Patterson, 1809 Oct. 1; 1.0 item; Jefferson, Thomas. (Box 4)
    - ALS to Robert Patterson, 1809 Dec. 19; 1.0 item; Jefferson, Thomas. (Box 4)
    - ALS to David Rittenhouse, 1796 July 3; 1.0 item; Jefferson, Thomas. (Box 4)
    - ALS to John Vaughan, 1805 Aug. 15; 1.0 item; Jefferson, Thomas. (Box 4)
    - ALS to the American Philosophical Society, 1802 Feb. 18; 1.0 item; Jolly Tar (pseud) (Box 4)
    - Extracts from log-book relative to sunspots, March 3-10, 1806, 1806 May 20; 1.0 item; Jones, William (Box 4)
    - Description of an improved air-pump (1), 1836 April 1; 1.0 item; Joslyn, Benjamin F. (Box 4)
    - Description of an improved air-pump (2), 1836 April 1; 2.0 items; Joslyn, Benjamin F. (Box 4)
      Note: contains diagram of (?) barometer/ air pump
    - Concerning ascertaining longitude at sea, 1791 Oct. 6; 1.0 item; Jourdan, W. Crowley (Box 4)
    - ALS to unidentified recipient, 1808 Mar. 28; 1.0 item; Kirk, Timothy (Box 4)
    - Concerning a ramming block, 1790 Oct. 13; 1.0 item; Kuhn, Ludwig Conrad (Box 4)
    - ALS to the American Philosophical Society, 1816 Sept. 15; 1.0 item; L., A. F. (Box 4)
      In German.
    - Concerning the Biblical verse "God said, let there be light", ca.1816; 1.0 item; L., A. F. (Box 4)
    - ALS to the American Philosophical Society. President, 1816 Oct. 6; 1.0 item; L., A. F. (Box 4)
    - ALS to the American Philosophical Society, n.d.; 1.0 item; L., A. F. (Box 4)
    - ALS [to the American Philosophical Society?], n.d.; 1.0 item; L., A. F. (Box 4)
    - ALS to Ferdinand R. Hassler, 1794 Oct. 12; 1.0 item; Lalande, Joseph Jérôme Le Fran, 1732-1807 (Box 4)
    - ALS to Thomas Jefferson, 1809 Sept. 19; 1.0 item; Lambert, William (Box OS)
    - ALS to Robert Patterson, 1810 Mar. 21; 1.0 item; Lambert, William (Box 4)
    - ALS to Robert Patterson, 1810 Mar. 25; 1.0 item; Lambert, William (Box 4)
    - ALS to John Vaughan, 1811 Feb. 20; 1.0 item; Lambert, William (Box 4)
    - ALS to John Vaughan, 1811 May 3; 1.0 item; Lambert, William (Box 4)
    - ALS to Thomas Jefferson, 1812 April 20; 1.0 item; Letter from Lambert to Jefferson, explaining new calculations for the diameter of the earth, and how locations calculated by previous measurements can be adjusted.; Lambert, William (Box 4)
    - ALS to Thomas Jefferson, 1812 April 23; 1.0 item; Abstract of paper for the American Philosophical Society by William Lambert concerning the location of various cities based on astronomical calculations.; Lambert, William (Box 4)
    - ALS to Thomas Jefferson, 1812 July 16; 1.0 item; Lambert, William (Box 4)
    - Concerning the correct longitude of Washington, 1813 Mar. 22; 1.0 item; Lambert, William (Box 4)
    - ALS to Thomas Jefferson, 1814 June 24; 1.0 item; Lambert, William (Box 4)
    - Concerning the correct longitude of Washington, 1815 May 17; 1.0 item; Lambert, William (Box 4)
    - ALS to Robert Patterson, 1815 May 18; 1.0 item; Lambert, William (Box 4)
    - ALS to Robert Patterson, 1818 July 08; 1.0 item; Lambert, William (Box 4)
    - ALS to Robert Patterson, 1818 Nov. 14; 1.0 item; Lambert, William (Box 4)
    - ALS to Robert Patterson, 1819 Aug. 10; 1.0 item; Lambert, William (Box 4)
    - ALS to Robert Patterson, 1819 Aug. 19; 1.0 item; Lambert, William (Box 4)
    - ALS to Robert Patterson, 1819 Aug. 24; 1.0 item; Lambert, William (Box 4)
    - ALS to Robert Patterson, 1821 July 31; 2.0 items; Lambert, William (Box OS)
    - ALS to Robert Patterson, 1821 Sept. 17; 1.0 item; Lambert, William (Box OS)
    - ALS to Robert Patterson, 1821 Sept. 27; 1.0 item; Lambert, William (Box 4)
    - ALS to Robert Patterson, 1822 June 25; 1.0 item; Lambert, William (Box 4)
    - ALS to Robert Patterson, 1822 June 29; 1.0 item; Lambert, William (Box 4)
    - ALS to the American Philosophical Society. President, 1825 July 4; 1.0 item; Lambert, William (Box 4)
    - ALS to Samuel Lewis Southard, 1826 Aug. 7; 1.0 item; Lambert, William (Box 4)
    - ALS to unidentified recipient, 1797; 4.0 items; Latrobe, Benjamin Henry, 1764-1820 (Box 4)
      Note: includes a letter from the Maryland Historical Society (1977) and a transcription of a letter from their collection of Latrobe's papers.
    - ALS to unidentified recipient, 1803 May 27; 1.0 item; Latrobe, Benjamin Henry, 1764-1820 (Box 4)
      Mechanics, Machinery, Engineering, etc. Mentions B. Franklin. Concerning steam engines.
    - ALS to Charles Willson Peale, 1807 Mar. 4; 1.0 item; Latrobe, Benjamin Henry, 1764-1820 (Box 4)
    - ALS to John Vaughan, 1807 Mar. 23; 2.0 items; Latrobe, Benjamin Henry, 1764-1820 (Box 4)
      Note: includes illustration "a block of Freestone from Acquia".
    - Concerning improvements in steam-engines, 1801 July 18; 3.0 items; Latrobe, Benjamin Henry, 1764-1820 (Box 4)
      Note: includes diagram.
    - Some observations concerning longitude, n.d.; 1.0 item; Laurie, Robert (Box 4)
    - ALS to Thomas Coombe, 1772 Dec. 29; 1.0 item; Leacock, John (Box 4)
    - ALS to the American Philosophical Society, 1772 Dec. 29; 1.0 item; Leacock, John (Box 4)
    - ALS to Brockbanks, 1813 Aug. 16; 1.0 item; Lee, Stephen (Box 4)
    - Rates of Mr. Hassler's chronometers by Brockbanks (1), 1813 Aug. 16; 2.0 items; Lee, Stephen (Box 4)
    - Rates of Mr. Hassler's chronometers by Brockbanks (2), 1813 Aug. 16; 2.0 items; Lee, Stephen (Box 4)
    - ALS to the American Philosophical Society, 1820; 1.0 item; Leeke, Charles (Box 4)
    - Meteorological observations made at Springmill, 1787 Dec.; 1.0 item; Legaux, Peter (Box 4)
    - Meteorological observations made at Springmill, 1789 May; 1.0 item; Legaux, Peter (Box 4)
    - Precis d'un ouvrage sur les hopitaux, 1777; 1.0 item; Le Roy, Jean Baptiste (Box 4)
    - Concerning the Empire of Morocco (1), 1821 June 15; 1.0 item; Lesseps, Matthieu Maximilien Prosper de (Box 4)
    - Concerning the Empire of Morocco (2), 1821 June 15; 1.0 item; Lesseps, Matthieu Maximilien Prosper de (Box 4)
    - Concerning the Empire of Morocco (3), 1821 June 15; 1.0 item; Lesseps, Matthieu Maximilien Prosper de (Box 4)
    - Description of several species of fish, 1817 Oct. 17; 1.0 item; Lesueur, Charles Alexandre, 1778-1846 (Box 4)
    - Letter to the Secretary of the A.P.S., 1802 April 16; 1.0 item (Box 4)
      Note: c.f. minutes p. 323